Documentation of Matrix Addition using MapReduce 

Pseudocode:

Take matrix A as an input from the console.
Take matrix B as as input from the console.

Matrix A:

1  2  3 ..... n
2  3  4 ..... n
...............
...............
n ........... n

Matrix B:

1  2  3 ..... n
2  3  4 ..... n
...............
...............
n ........... n


Validate the Rows of matrix A = Rows of matrix B
Validate the Columns of matrix A = Columns of matrix B

Result:

Rows: n=n;
Columns : n=n;

Map Operation:
Apply Map operation on the give matrices A,B.

The output of the Map Operation will be a set of (Key, Value) pairs.

The Key will be the row number and the value will be the set of values with in a row.


Result: (Key, V[])

Key will be the row value and V will be the set of values in that particular row.

Now pass this Key value pair which is the output of a Map operation to the Reduce operation.
Here is a place where we perform Arithematic Addition.

The reduce operation will be having two key value pairs each for a matrix.

From each (key,value) pair => consider the set of values (vector/ array) having the same key and add the elements accordingly.

As the two matrices A and B are generated as a key value pairs. We will be having two set of of values whose key is equal. (One from the matrix A and one from the matrix B)

ie; We will be taking the two set of values from the Vector/array and will be adding the two values as per their indices.

Now the obtained results will also be stored into a vector/array and will be associated with the same key number.

As the Key is the row number, the display of the result can be done accordingly.

So, the output of the reduce operation is also a (key,value) pair after summing up.
